<document title="What's New">


    If you have previously used JRat, you will definitely notice some differences in
    recent versions.  During JRat's history, it has become clear what features provide
    the most value, and those features have been focused on.

    <section>
        <h>No Injection Step</h>

        Java 5 has given us JVMPI, which provides a super easy way to hook into
        a JVM's class loading infrastructure. The result is that you can "install"
        JRat now with a single command line argument. Nice.
    </section>

    <section>
        <h>File Configuration</h>

        Previous versions of JRat made extensive use of system properties to control
        features, though an XML file could be optionally used.

        This model has been replaced with an <b>jrat.xml</b> file that is <i>always</i> used.
        If this file is not found at statup, a default file will be created and used.
    </section>

    <section>
        <h>No Separate Downloads</h>

        Previously, it was necessary to download BCEL to use JRat.

        While JRat still depends on several other open source projects (
        <a href="http://asm.objectweb.org/">ASM</a>
        and
        <a href="http://swinglabs.org/">SwingX</a>
        ),
        these libraries are now embedded within the JRat jar.  This is done with a fine
        open source tool called
        <a href="http://www.tonicsystems.com/products/jarjar/">Jar Jar Links</a>.

    </section>

    <section>
        <h>Focus on the TreeHandler</h>

        The most useful handler has always been the
        <i>TreeHandler</i>,
        but several others were implemented as well.

        Much more attention is now being paid to the TreeHandler, which is provides about 90%
        of JRat's value.

        You can still write your own handlers, or configure multiple handlers, but the
        TreeHandler has been promoted to first class status.  This is also true of
    </section>
    <section>
        <h>Focus on Bytecode Instrumentation</h>

        Bytecode injection is <b>the</b> preferred way to use JRat.
        Support for programmatic instrumentation and possibly AOP will be phased out.
    </section>

    <section>
        <h>ASM is in, BCEL is out</h>

        JRat now uses ObjectWeb's ASM library to perform bytecode injection.  ASM fully
        supports the Java 5 class file format.  
    </section>

    <section>
        <h>HTTP Server</h>

        While still under active development, the built in HTTP server has been vastly
        improved upon. It is expected that JRat will begin taking greater advantage of
        this interface.
    </section>

    <section>
        <h>Output Format</h>
        JRat previously produced output (for the TreeHandler) in XML. The XML format has been
        replaced with a binary (serialization based) format.  At some point in the future it
        may be possible to export data to XML, HTML, or another format.
    </section>



</document>