<document title="What's New">


    If you have previously used JRat, you will definitely notice some differences in
    recent versions.

    <section>
        <h>No Injection Step</h>

        Java 5 has given us JVMPI, which provides a super easy way to hook into
        a JVM's class loading infrastructure. The result is that you can "install"
        JRat now with a single command line argument. Sweet.
    </section>

    <section>
        <h>File Configuration</h>

        Previous versions of JRat made extensive use of system properties to control featured.
        This model has been replaced with an XML configuration file that is always used.
        If no configuration file is found at statup, a default file will be created and used.
    </section>

    <section>
        <h>Focus on #1 Handler</h>

        In the past, the most useful handler was the
        <i>TreeHandler</i>
        but several other
        handlers were supported as well. More attention is now being paid to the TreeHandler,
        which is where 90% of JRat's value always was. You can still write your own handlers,
        or configure multiple handlers, but the TreeHandler has been promoted to
        first class status.
    </section>
    <section>
        <h>Focus on Bytecode Instrumentation</h>
        Bytecode injection is <b>the</b> prefered way to use JRat.
        Support for programatic intrumentation and possibly AOP will be phased out.
    </section>

    <section>
        <h>ASM is in, BCEL is out</h>
        JRat now uses ObjectWeb's ASM library to perform bytecode injection.
    </section>
    <section>
        <h>HTTP Server</h>

        While still under active development, the built in HTTP server has been vastly
        improved upon. It is expected that JRat will begin taking greater advantage of
        this interface.
    </section>

    <section>
        <h>Output Format</h>
        JRat previously produced output (for the TreeHandler) in XML. The XML format has been
        replaced with a binary (serialization based) format. At some point in the future it
        may be possible to export data to XML, HTML, or another format.
    </section>



</document>